<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>viggyravi</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on viggyravi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best of Both Worlds: Reticulate for R and Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021/05/09/best-of-both-worlds-reticulate-for-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/05/09/best-of-both-worlds-reticulate-for-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>Are All Programming Languages Equal?After programming with R for about a semester, I found it exponentially difficult to do exploratory data analysis in Python - a language I’ve been using for years now. R is a great programming language to perform many statistical tests; moreover, the simplicity of tidyverse makes it so easy to do exploratory data analysis. Also, there’s piping - I’m not sure who thought of that, but its my favorite programming tool I’ve learned so far!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Covid Outcome Prediction</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>0.0 IntroductionA health crisis of massive proportion such as the current COVID-19 pandemic has provided us ample opportunity to reflect on our healthcare system and how we can strengthen it. As we heard at the beginning of the pandemic, healthcare officials want to ‘flatten the curve’ to ensure sufficient supplies will be available to patients, thus minimizing casualties. For this report, I will look into data provided from COVID-19 patients, provided by the Mexican government (link), to build a model to predict hospitalization rates and hopefully provide insight on where to best allocate resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Tidying Up Plastic</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>0.0 IntroductionNo one can go a day without using plastic. It has become an essential item in many of the products we buy or use regularly, furniture to clothing to electronics. Because plastic is so ubiquitous, it becomes easy at times to forget about the impact it has on the environment. Through this project, I hope to learn about the different types of plastic (I keep forgetting what all the recycling numbers mean) and their main producers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Check out some of my R projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis: Understanding Plastic Waste in Countries
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction: COVID-19 Hospitalization Prediction
  --</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
